When you're choosing how to display your data,
عندما تختار كيفية عرض بياناتك،
it's important to not only think about what you put
من المهم ألا تفكر فقط في ما تضعه في
into a visual but also what you're going to leave out.
صورة مرئية، بل أيضًا ما ستتركه.
This brings us to chart junk.
وهذا يؤدي إلى الحصول على رسم بياني غير هام.
Chart junk is a term that refers to all visual elements in charts
الرسم البياني غير الهام هو مصطلح يشير إلى جميع العناصر المرئية في المخططات
and graphs that are not necessary to
والرسوم البيانية غير الضرورية
comprehend the information represented in that chart.
لفهم المعلومات الممثلة في هذا المخطط.
They might also distract the viewer from the information you're trying to provide.
قد يشتت هذا انتباه المشاهد أيضًا عن المعلومات التي تحاول تقديمها.
Markings and visual elements can be called chart junk if they're not
يمكن تسمية العلامات والعناصر المرئية رسمًا بيانيًا غير هام إذا لم تكن
a part of the minimum set of visuals necessary to communicate clearly.
جزءًا من مجموعة الحد الأدنى من العناصر المرئية اللازمة للتواصل بوضوح.
Let's go through a few examples.
دعونا نعرض بعض الأمثلة.
Examples of chart junk include those listed here.
تشمل أمثلة الرسم البياني غير الهام تلك المدرجة هنا.
Heavy or dark grid lines, unnecessary text,
خطوط الشبكة الثقيلة أو المعتمة، والنص غير الضروري،
pictures surrounding or within graphs,
والصور المحيطة أو الموجودة داخل الرسوم البيانية،
shading or 3D components,
أو التظليل أو المكونات ثلاثية الأبعاد،
or ornamented chart or axes.
أو المخطط المزخرف أو المحاور.
This example shows how charged junk obscures the data,
يوضح هذا المثال كيف أن الرسم غير المرغوب فيه يحجب البيانات،
which is just five simple numbers.
وهي عبارة عن خمسة أرقام بسيطة فقط.
You can imagine this as a one to five scale rating at a restaurant,
يمكنك تخيل هذا كتقييم من واحد إلى خمسة في أحد المطاعم،
and the height of each bar is
وارتفاع كل شريط هو
how many individuals provide the rating shown at the bottom.
عدد الأفراد الذين يقدمون التقييم الموضح في الأسفل.
We see here, ornamented chart axes that obscure the actual
نرى هنا، محاور تخطيط مزخرف تحجب القيم
values,and also the use of textures on both the bars and the background.
الفعلية، وكذلك استخدام القوام على كل من الأشرطة والخلفية.
Another type of charred junk skews the message
نوع آخر من الرسم غير المرغوب فيه يزيح
and makes it difficult to understand the real data being displayed.
الرسالة ويجعل من الصعب فهم البيانات الحقيقية التي يتم عرضها.
The teeth here are an example of this type of chart junk.
الأسنان هنا هي مثال على هذا النوع من الرسم البياني غير الهام.